# MUHAMMAD SHULHAN JIHADI

mail.shulhan@qmail.com | linkedin.com/in/mshulhani | github.com/shlhni/ | Yogyakarta, Indonesia

## **PROFILE**

I hold a Bachelor degree in Oceanography with a strong background on satellite remote sensing, GIS, cartography, and ecological modelling. I have a proven track records of both technical and managerial skills developed through conducting research, experience leading teams, and writing scientific articles.

### **EDUCATION**

### **Universitas Diponegoro: B.Sc Oceanography**

**Semarang, Aug 2019 - June 2023** 

- Bachelor of Science B.Sc, Oceanography | Final GPA: 3.58/4.00
- Specialized in marine ecological modelling using diverse remote sensing data and GIS methods.
- Thesis: Modelling of Pygmy Blue Whale (*Balaenoptera musculus brevicauda*) Migration Corridor in Savu and Banda Sea Using Circuit Theory (<u>read</u>)

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## Research Assistant: Universitas Diponegoro

Semarang, May 2023 - Present

- Assisted Prof. Muhammad Zainuri DEA, in conducting research along the northern coast of Central Java,
   with a primary focus on marine ecology and coastal environments.
- Led multiple teams in conducting field surveys across locations including Pekalongan, Jepara, Pemalang, and Batang.
- Aided in drafting proposals, budget plans, timelines, and team management to ensure efficient project execution and alignment with research goals.
- Co-authored some research articles:
  - 1. Determination of chlorophyll-a and its distribution in the waters of the mangrove forest rehabilitation area in Mojo Estuaria, Pemalang. http://dx.doi.org/10.14710/jkt.v27i2.23253
  - 2. Geospatial Modeling of the Nitrate Distribution as an Indicator of Aquatic Fertility in the Lagoon Waters of the Mangrove Information Center (PIM), Pekalongan. <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.14710/jkt.v27i3.24081">http://dx.doi.org/10.14710/jkt.v27i3.24081</a>
  - 3. Books: Buletin Geomaritime XIV Juni 2022 Parangtritis Geomaritime Science Technopark

## WORK EXPERIENCE

### Hydrographic Surveyor: PT Fifan Jaya Makmur

East Nusa Tenggara, July 2024-Aug 2024

- Conducted Hydrographic survey such as bathymetric survey, seafloor & sub-bottom profiling, and current measurement in West Manggarai and Maumere, East Nusa Tenggara
- Operated marine instrument such as Marine GPS Hemisphere 330, Odom Hydrotrac II, and Current Meter
   Valeport 106 while also assisting to use Side-Scan Sonar and Sub-bottom profiler
- Used software such as Hypack, Pocket Max, and Valeport Data Logger

#### **GIS Technician: BRGM**

# Semarang, July 2023-Sept 2023

BRGM is Peatland And Mangrove Restoration Agency of Republic of Indonesia. This projects is a collaboration between BRGM and Universitas Diponegoro for National Mangrove Map.

- Processed Sentinel-2 Image using Google Earth Engine and ArcGIS
- Delineated vast mangrove forest for East Kalimantan region (around 127,346.92 km2)
- Providing guidance and directions for the junior technicians

### **Teaching Assistant: Universitas Diponegoro**

#### **Semarang, Aug 2021 - Nov 2022**

- Assisted teaching practical skill in several subject: Remote Sensing, GIS, Coastal Multihazard, and
  Disaster Mitigation. Provided hands-on guidance and mentoring to students, explained complex concepts
  in a clear and concise manner
- Coordinated a team of 10 assistants, overseeing the planning and execution of practicum sessions for younger students (100+) across three different departments.
- Developed tailored curriculum and lesson plans, aligning them with the specific learning objectives and needs of each practicum.

### ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCE

### **REGISTER UNDIP**

Remote Sensing and Geographic Information System Technology and Research is a student research club in the Faculty of Fisheries and Marine Science, Universitas Diponegoro, that focuses on the usage of satellite and geospatial analysis for coastal and marine application.

#### President

## **Semarang, Jan 2022 - Dec 2022**

- Led a student research club comprised of 45 members, fostering a collaborative and growth-oriented environment.
- Developed a comprehensive learning curriculum for the organization, incorporating the ctting edge tech and sconcepts in remote sensing and geographic information system technology
- Directed the organization to overcome challenges during the post-COVID transition, conceptualizing strategies and initiatives to adapt effectively
- Supervised the execution of projects and programmes, ensuring their successfuland timely completion.

## **Research and Development staff**

### Semarang, March 2021 - Dec 2021

- Organized webinars and sharing sessions to improve members' research competency
- Executed flexible methods for conducting organizational programs during the COVID situation
- Disseminated newest technology for collaboration with external partners
- Highest annual performance among members of 2021 period

# **SKILLS**

Language:

Native / Mother tongue(s) : Bahasa Indonesia, Javanese

Other languages : English (C1/IELTS Band:7.5) – British Council – 09/12/2023

## Digital Skills:

Geographic Information System : ArcGIS, QGIS,

Remote Sensing : Google Earth Engine, SNAP
Programming Language : R, Python, Julia, HTML, CSS

## • Training and Workshops:

<u>Using Spatial Data for Biodiversity</u> – United Nations Development Programme – 11/09/2024

<u>Invasive Species Monitoring with Remote Sensing</u> – NASA 14/08/2024 – 28/08/2024 <u>Spatial Data Science: The New Frontier In Analytics</u> – Esri 28/10/2021 – 09/12/2021 <u>Species Distribution Modeling With Remote Sensing</u> – NASA 12/08/2021 – 19/08/2021

<u>Cartography</u> - Esri 06/02/2021 - 20/03/2021

<u>Hyperspectral Data For Land And Coastal Systems</u> – NASA 19/01/2021 – 02/02/2021